<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>yeching's website</title><link href="http://yeching.info/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://yeching.info/feeds/english-learning.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://yeching.info/</id><updated>2016-03-25T00:00:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>Johan Cruyff</title><link href="http://yeching.info/johan-cruyff.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-03-25T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>yeching</name></author><id>tag:yeching.info,2016-03-25:johan-cruyff.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="图片" src="http://yeching.info/images/Johan-Cruyff-4.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="图片" src="http://yeching.info/images/Johan-Cruyff-3.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a fans of FC Barcelona for three years,I often focus on the news about the Barcelona.This morning,I as usual enter the barcelona website.The title of "Johan Cruyff passes away at 68" hits me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following content is from Barcelona's official website .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="johan-cruyff-passes-away-at-68"&gt;Johan Cruyff passes away at 68&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FC Barcelona legend Johan Cruyff passed away on Thursday 24 March following a long battle with cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cruyff arrived at the club in August 1973 from Ajax, renowned as one of the best players in the world. Barça soon began to reap the rewards as the Dutch magician helped Barça to the league title in his first season, and went on to win his second and third Ballon d’Or. With his intelligent play, superb technique and leadership, he quickly became an icon for Barça.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His acrobatic strike against Atlético Madrid and the 5-0 win at the Santiago Bernabeu in 1974, among many other great moments, will live long in the memory of Barça fans. In 1978, after winning the Copa del Rey, Cruyff left the club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten years later, however, he would return as manager. He was in the dugout for eight seasons, during which time he led the club through its most successful ever period up until that point. He won four consecutive league titles and guided the club to its first ever European Cup in May 1992 at Wembley, among other successes. He formed the side that would go onto be known as the legendary ‘Dream Team’, a team that amazed everyone with their extraordinary style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1996, he left the Barça bench, and in 1999 was chosen as the player of the century in Europe. He was a figure actively involved with Catalonia too, and in September 2006, the Government of Catalonia awarded him with the Cross of St. George, and he later became the manager of the Catalan national football team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="letter-from-the-presidents-of-fc-barcelona-to-johan-cruyff"&gt;Letter from the presidents of FC Barcelona to Johan Cruyff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="图片" src="http://yeching.info/images/Johan-Cruyff-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barcelona, 24 March 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Johan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Johan Cruyff's death is sad news for the entire world of football. His individual and collective achievements made him one of the best players and coaches in history and the professional and personal footprint he left at our club is enormous. First and foremost, we want to convey our sincerest condolences to the Cruyff family and to all the Club's players and staff who, throughout his various stages as a player and coach, shared emotions, efforts and the joys of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a day like today, every FC Barcelona fan will recall their own memories of and experiences relating to Cruyff as both a leader and as a symbol. We, as presidents of FC Barcelona, have the immense honour to give thanks, on behalf of Barcelona supporters everywhere, to a brilliant and audacious man who decisively marked the trajectory of the club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are thankful to Cruyff for his work as a player and as a coach, and for the titles he achieved. But above all, we are thankful for the intangibles which are still alive today and which will endure into the future, for they are worth more than all those titles; Cruyff endowed us with high levels of self-esteem and set a new course for the success of FC Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Cruyff we began to play differently, breaking new ground and innovating. With him, both as a player and coach, we established our own style on the field, what is traditionally known as 'total football,' the Barça style everyone admires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arrival of Cruyff altered the history of Barça. He contributed decisively to a change of mentality. He got us to keep our heads up and to see that no opponent was invincible, that we could attain what we were aiming for. Cruyff was an icon who explained, better than anyone, that Barça is more than a club. He did it simply and based in reality, and always moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without Cruyff's unabashed and non-conformist spirit, we quite possibly wouldn't have become the greatest club in the world. So, again, thank you, Johan. Thanks to the man who was admired, thanks to the social icon, thanks to the football superstar. Thank you for your audacity, thank you for your expertise, and thank you for having chosen Barça and Barcelona in the same way that, for Barça and Catalonia, you have always been, and will always be, one of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Johan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="fc-barcelona-mourns-the-death-of-johan-cruyff"&gt;FC Barcelona mourns the death of Johan Cruyff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="图片" src="http://yeching.info/images/Johan-Cruyff-2.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The club expresses its condolences towards its legendary former player and manager who will always be remembered in the highest regard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FC Barcelona would like to express its pain and sorrow at the passing away of Johan Cruyff (Amsterdam, 25/04/1947 - Barcelona, 24/03/2016), who was both an FC Barcelona player and a coach and who will forever be a legend at the Club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FC Barcelona wishes to send its most heartfelt sympathy to Johan Cruyff’s family at such a painful moment, a sentiment which the Club members, fans and the whole world of football and sport will share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rest in peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you Johan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="图片" src="http://yeching.info/images/Camp-Nou-Flag.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flags at Camp Nou have been placed at half-mast.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="足球"></category><category term="English"></category></entry><entry><title>Learning English</title><link href="http://yeching.info/xue-xi-ying-yu.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-01-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>yeching</name></author><id>tag:yeching.info,2016-01-22:xue-xi-ying-yu.html</id><summary type="html">
&lt;h2 id="_1"&gt;目标与兴趣&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;从初中到现在，我也学了将近10年的英语。一直以来，学习英语好像一直是为了考试才学的，纵使有时候考了不错的分数，但是要是别人一问英语实际正常使用怎么样啊，那个心里真是没底气。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;其实说实话，我对英语挺感兴趣的。为什么感兴趣还学的不咋样呢？因为除了考试，我未曾感觉到英语对我的重要性，让我有一个非要学习它的理由，所以即使有兴趣也不足以推动你去自我学习，发自内心的想要去学习它,。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;真正让我想要好好学习英语的时候，是在大二下学期，这个时期自己对计算机技术挺感兴趣了，但是好多的文档手册都是英文的，外国的最新技术博客等都是英文的，自己不得不去看。密密麻麻的全是英文字母，第一眼看上去，就让人有想要放弃的感觉。这个时候如果仅有兴趣的话，恐怕你早以放弃。&lt;strong&gt;兴趣它是让你做一件事情很容易感到开心，容易知足且有成就感。当一件事情一上来就让你感受到恐惧和困难的话，兴趣它的力量就有点小了。个人一直认为兴趣它在顺境的情况下，的确有着大的驱动力，当在逆境的时候就显得有点微不足道了。&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;举个例子：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有两个小孩，都特别喜欢学习武术，Ａ学习武术的想法是：他感觉学习武术非常酷，尤其是当他看见其他人使出一招招高难度动作后，获得周围观众掌声时，他更按耐不住想要学习武术了。而Ｂ的想法是：在学校，别人总是欺负他，让他干他不愿意干的事，他想要通过学习武术，摆脱这样的窘境。一天，Ａ和Ｂ同时来到一家武馆拜师学艺，第二天，他们开始学习武术了，师傅教他们扎马步，第三天还是扎马步，往后还是不断的扎马步走树桩，同时逐渐加长时间和加大负重，偶尔也学学简单的招式。这样的情况持续到十五天的时候，Ａ放弃了，他受不了这样的学习武术，他觉得这和他想要的武术不一样，而Ｂ坚持住了，难道Ｂ知道这是学习武术的基础，需要扎实的基本功？最重要的是Ｂ他不想被别人欺负，他想要通过学习武术让自己变得强大，能够保护自己。在这15天学习的过程中，他也感觉到自己好像更有自信了，往后的剧情自己想象......&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;刚开始，让我能够硬着头皮继续往下看的原因是，它对我重要。仔细一看内容，好多都是能够看明白的，只有少数的陌生词汇不认识，我知道开始是内心的恐惧让我放弃了，连尝试都没有尝试(&lt;strong&gt;对于渴望而有未知的东西，你要敢于迈出第一步&lt;/strong&gt;)，当内心的恐惧消除以后，此时兴趣就开始发挥作用了，坚持，专注什么的就相当容易了.虽然现在还没达到非常优秀的地步，但可以预见会变得越来越好。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="_2"&gt;时间关系&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有时候感觉学了好几年的英语还不如别人强化训练几个月的，刨去方法，天赋等因素，另一个要谈到的那就是有效学习时间的问题了。我们一直以来用于学习英语的时间到底有多少呢？就是每周英语课的时间，而每周的加起来的总时间最多不过10个小时（一天两小时），并且这10个小时还是分割开来的。那么就会存在这样的情况，昨天的学的东西到今天忘了好多了，今天学的可能又是建立在昨天的基础上的，导致今天的没有跟上或听明白；同时每次开始上英语课的时候，你从汉语思维转到英语思维中来还需要一定时间的，也就是说你还需要一定时间来进入学习英语的状态，或者你上课困了，睡了一觉没有学习等等一系列问题。导致你的一周实际有效学习时间也就几个小时了（算４小时），一年下来也就4乘以40周等于160小时。根据人的记忆特性，你可能经过一个暑假或寒假没有复习，基本上又一假回到解放前了，学了几年你一直没有什么进步，学来学去还是只会刚开始学英语的几句话，什么how are you 或者nice to meet you.从始至终我们就一直没有进入到学习英语的状态。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;接下来再来看强化训练几个月的方式，这种方法可取的之处就是它解决了我们之前的遇到的问题。首先它是连续性的学习(一天学习八个小时，且比较有针对性)，根据人的学习记忆特性，有助于思维的养成；同时在这连续的时间段内，你可以不断重复得到训练，可以发现错误，纠正从而产生正累积效应（可以更加有针对性）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="_3"&gt;我的一些方法（用中学）：&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;看技术文档，查看wiki，阅读书籍，文章，翻译一些喜欢的东西&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;音乐，对话，电影，纪录片，&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt;英文环境，目标明确有针对，重复训练有提高，时间长短看自己，进步与否看行动&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="_4"&gt;总结：&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;首先&lt;strong&gt;明确你的目标&lt;/strong&gt;，这样你就会非常重视他，时刻将它放在心上。之后就是不断使用学习，不断犯错，不断纠正，体会学习给你带来的收获，从而更加坚定你的信心，让兴趣引导你前进。语言类的就是在不断使用，不断重复从而达到一种让你有种脱口而出的感觉，你并不需要非常刻意经过思考从中文的翻译为英语。我们可以想想婴儿学东西的方式，我们刚出生下来，到慢慢的自己会说话的过程中，我们并不是准备充分了才开始说话的，而是不断使用中学习的（模仿，犯错，学习），最后形成自己的思维。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;还有就是&lt;strong&gt;有效学习&lt;/strong&gt;时间要足够长，总是三天打鱼，两天晒网，时不时学一下，基本上是没有效果的。必须自己主动的学习，而不是好像被迫的推着前行。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All along, the action is the best way &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go-Go-Go&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action-Action-Action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;最后来碗热腾腾的鸡汤：&lt;/strong&gt;你是否有这样干过一件事情，每天你起早贪黑，每天你废寝忘食，每天你满腔热血的拼搏，每天你不顾一切的拼搏，坚定不移而有满怀斗志的朝着你的目标前进，只为那一刻，而那一刻的过程总是孤独而又困难重重的。如果你不曾这样，就请你闭嘴前行亦或是呆在生硬的现实之中。&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="感悟"></category><category term="English"></category></entry></feed>